What is abstraction?

Abstarction is only knowing the necessary details and hiding the rest.

For example, sending SMS where you type the text and send the message. You don't know the internal processing about the message delivery.

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Is Abstract class related to Abstraction ? 

Abstraction is similar to the concept of a black box. Input goes in, black box does something, output comes out. It doesn't matter what happens in the black box, all you have to know is that it works. A real life example of this is java's hash function, all the user has to know is that it hashes the input value, it doesn't matter to the user how the number gets hashed. The black box is the abstraction. The point is you don't have to know how it works, just that it does.

Abstract classes (at least in Java) are a mixture between interfaces and full OOP classes. An interface defines methods that any extending class must have, its an agreement in the code that it will implement the interface properly and assures everything will work as expected. An abstract class has these empty methods(agreements) and also has fully implemented methods that can be called.

==========================================================================================================================


Can interfaces have normal variables ?

Like a class, an interface can have methods and variables, but the methods declared in an interface are by default abstract (only method signature, no body).

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Can interfaces have methods with definitions ? if so how ? or what ?

Yes, it is mandatory to implement all the methods in a class that implements an interface until and unless that class is declared as an abstract class.

There are only two choices −

	Implement every method defined by the interface.
	Declare the class as an abstract class, as a result, forces you to subclass the class (and implement the missing methods) before you can create any 	objects.

The only case the class do not need to implement all methods in the interface is when any class in its inheritance tree has already provided concrete (i.e. non-abstract) method implementations then the subclass is under no obligation to re-implement those methods. The subclass may not implement the interface at all and just method signature is matched.

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

How to implement multiple inheritance using interfaces?

An interface contains variables and methods like a class but the methods in an interface are abstract by default unlike a class. Multiple inheritance by interface occurs if a class implements multiple interfaces or also if an interface itself extends multiple interfaces.

ex:

interface AnimalEat {
   void eat();
}
interface AnimalTravel {
   void travel();
}
class Animal implements AnimalEat, AnimalTravel {
   public void eat() {
      System.out.println("Animal is eating");
   }
   public void travel() {
      System.out.println("Animal is travelling");
   }
}
public class Demo {
   public static void main(String args[]) {
      Animal a = new Animal();
      a.eat();
      a.travel();
   }
}

-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Interfaces also can have few things - what are those things can interfaces have apart from abstract methods?

Type of methods: Interface can have only abstract methods. An abstract class can have abstract and non-abstract methods. 
Final Variables: Variables declared in a Java interface are by default final. An abstract class may contain non-final variables.
Type of variables: Abstract class can have final, non-final, static and non-static variables. The interface has only static and final variables.
Implementation: Abstract class can provide the implementation of the interface. Interface can’t provide the implementation of an abstract class
Inheritance vs Abstraction: A Java interface can be implemented using the keyword “implements” and an abstract class can be extended using the keyword “extends”.
Multiple implementations: An interface can extend another Java interface only, an abstract class can extend another Java class and implement multiple Java interfaces
Accessibility of Data Members: Members of a Java interface are public by default. A Java abstract class can have class members like private, protected, etc.